TAYLOR FOSTER

Software Engineer

📞 212-312-7001 🍳 Email 🕜 github.io/name-surname 👂 Austin, TX

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer

2021 - Present

Blackbaud

Austin, TX

- Successfully converted whole project from python 2 to 3.8.0
- Scripted unique test plans, test scripts and processes to remove previously known redundancy by 40% and ensured predictable outcomes
- Developed a desktop application to automate database testing process, improved efficiency by 65%
- · Automated process to create usage graphs, saving \$500,000 / year & increasing accuracy

Senior Software Engineer

2017 - 2021

Wayfair Austin, TX

- Moved the automation solution into a commercial software (\$60k/year)
- Designed and developed reusable software components which used in 3 different project with reducing development effort by 50%
- Re-engineered critical modules within a sprint to rely on a centralized library to optimize performance by 68%
- Rated with the best annual performance rating for all the years during my stint; given to top ~5% employees

Software Developer

2015 - 2017

Target Austin, TX

- Helped to increase the accuracy of the reporting systems by 4%
- Delivered configuration management tools to track server settings for performance testing which saved 25% of initial machine setup
- Developed monitor reports that are using in-memory cache, updating the data shown to the user every 1 second
- Optimized customer resources and reduce turnaround time by 20%
- Performed root cause analysis for more than 10 issues to identify bugs and rolled out fixes to production within 24 hours

Junior Software Engineer

2013 - 2015

Redfin Austin, TX

- Fueled additional revenue stream through responsive customer support, generating \$18k in new license sales within first three weeks of new release
- Improved user interfaces by updating menus to be more intuitive, increasing sales by 5%
- Reduced the time by 75% to process 70,000 to 1, 00,000 instruments from 16+ seconds to less than 4 seconds by redesigning the algorithm
- Wrote optimized scripts for data-heavy & processing heavy task automation
- Spearheaded the revamp of tech stack which resulted in 40% decrease in server costs

EDUCATION

Executive MBA, Engineering Management

2010 - 2011

The University of Arizona

Tucson, AZ

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

2006 - 2009

North Carolina Wesleyan College

Rocky Mount, NC



KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Spearheaded a \$12M software project

from design to distribution as a senior software engineer in a 12-people team

30% improved query efficiency

by designing and fully revising the two largest MySQL databases

Coordinated a year-long release of a six-part platform project

with marketing, BA, QA, and sales department.

Chatbot implementation

Developed a chatbot which helped customer to reduce costs by 240% in their customer service department

SKILLS

Tools

Java · C++ · Python · Perl · mySQL ·

ASP.NET

Operating Systems

Unix · Solaris · Linux · Windows

STRENGTHS

Was awarded a gold medal for 5 years of consecutive excellence in academics (2005-2010)

★ Corporate Social Responsibility

Volunteered in the CSR team for Amadeus, organized tuition platforms for the underprivileged. Designed confluence page for book drives, etc.